<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Optics on Jaka Pribošek</title>
    <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/tags/optics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Optics on Jaka Pribošek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaka.pribosek.com/tags/optics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt Azimuth rig</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/altazmount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/altazmount/</guid>
      <description>-tbd-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro Tracker</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/astrotracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/astrotracker/</guid>
      <description>-tbd-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shack Hartmann Sensor</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/shackhartmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/shackhartmann/</guid>
      <description>I developed two versions of a Shack Hartmann wavefront sensor and wrote a custom image processing algorithms to estimate the optical aberrations of optical system. The working principle is simple. The input wavefront is divided into several different channels, each focused with its own microlens. Sensor is placed in the focal plane of the microlens array. Any local tilt of the wavefront shifts the point from its central position. A custom Python algorithm finds center of each individual spots, orders them on the grid and performs the modal analysis, projection on the orthogonal Zernike polynomials basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spherometer</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/spherometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/spherometer/</guid>
      <description>Spherometer is an instrument used to measure the sag of the lens and inspect the progress during a rough grinding process. As a measurement head, Mitutoyo 543-390B ID-C112XB is used which provides absolute accuracy with micrometer resolution. Aluminium holder was CNC machined from a 10mm thick scrap sheet. The setup is calibrated on a flat calibrated surface plate and used to asses sag of the telescope mirror during the grinding process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirror grinding machine</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/grindingmachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/grindingmachine/</guid>
      <description>Grinding a telescope mirror with your bare hands until its surface is matching a desired shape to few nanometer is a unique experience.
I decided to design, construct and built an 12inch travel telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Microoptics</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/microoptics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/microoptics/</guid>
      <description>I built several microlens arrays with different technologies, reflow lithography, with subsequent reactive ion etching, electromagnetic imprinting to produce molds, used in an embossing process to produce lenses, and last, ion exchange process to change the refractive index using KNO3 and AGNO3 molten salt baths.
I used a lens to build a Shack-Hartmann sensor, which was built entirely from scratch. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LED Sign</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/leddisplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/leddisplay/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made this LED display for a friend of mine, who happens to be a big football fan.
A stand was carved out of spruce with a 6mm ballnose mill. The stock material has been mount inclined 20° on the CNC while the pocket was curved. The display is made out of plexi glass, engraved with 60° V-cutter, dived 0.5mm in material, with 0.75mm pitch. Underneath the plexiglass, there are 6 green LEDs, secretly placed in the pocket in the stand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deformable Mirror</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/deformable-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/deformable-mirror/</guid>
      <description>As a side project of my PhD, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed an adaptive optical system with a custom built deformable mirror. Deformable mirror was developed out of a piezo buzzer to which at the frontside, a small coated objective glass, ground to the round shape has been bonded. Piezo electrode has been segmented into four electrically isolated segments. By applying different voltages to the segments, the curvature of the mirror can be controlled.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>