<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wavefront on Jaka Pribošek</title>
    <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/tags/wavefront/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wavefront on Jaka Pribošek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaka.pribosek.com/tags/wavefront/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt Azimuth rig</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/altazmount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/altazmount/</guid>
      <description>-tbd-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astro Tracker</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/astrotracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/astrotracker/</guid>
      <description>-tbd-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shack Hartmann Sensor</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/shackhartmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/shackhartmann/</guid>
      <description>I developed two versions of a Shack Hartmann wavefront sensor and wrote a custom image processing algorithms to estimate the optical aberrations of optical system. The working principle is simple. The input wavefront is divided into several different channels, each focused with its own microlens. Sensor is placed in the focal plane of the microlens array. Any local tilt of the wavefront shifts the point from its central position. A custom Python algorithm finds center of each individual spots, orders them on the grid and performs the modal analysis, projection on the orthogonal Zernike polynomials basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spherometer</title>
      <link>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/spherometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:55:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaka.pribosek.com/home/spherometer/</guid>
      <description>Spherometer is an instrument used to measure the sag of the lens and inspect the progress during a rough grinding process. As a measurement head, Mitutoyo 543-390B ID-C112XB is used which provides absolute accuracy with micrometer resolution. Aluminium holder was CNC machined from a 10mm thick scrap sheet. The setup is calibrated on a flat calibrated surface plate and used to asses sag of the telescope mirror during the grinding process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>